[
  {
    "id": 3201,
    "question": "partida",
    "questionDetails": "Las trompetas señalaban la partida del rey.",
    "answer": "departure, heading, item",
    "answerDetails": "The trumpets signaled the departure of the king."
  },
  {
    "id": 3202,
    "question": "lento",
    "questionDetails": "Ella era más bien un lector lento.",
    "answer": "slow",
    "answerDetails": "She was rather a slow reader."
  },
  {
    "id": 3203,
    "question": "rompe",
    "questionDetails": "Siempre se rompe la suya.",
    "answer": "breaks, smashes, shattering",
    "answerDetails": "He always breaks his own."
  },
  {
    "id": 3204,
    "question": "conocida",
    "questionDetails": "Joanna es una conocida mía.",
    "answer": "acquaintance",
    "answerDetails": "Joanna is an acquaintance of mine."
  },
  {
    "id": 3205,
    "question": "lee",
    "questionDetails": "Lee la letra pequeña de tu contrato.",
    "answer": "read",
    "answerDetails": "Read the fine print in your contract."
  },
  {
    "id": 3206,
    "question": "infancia",
    "questionDetails": "Ese olor me trae recuerdos de mi infancia.",
    "answer": "childhood",
    "answerDetails": "That smell brings me memories of my childhood."
  },
  {
    "id": 3207,
    "question": "sabés",
    "questionDetails": "Sabés que puedes tener intimidad de muchas maneras?",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "You know you can be intimate in many ways?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3208,
    "question": "asistente",
    "questionDetails": "Todos los asistentes dijeron que la junta salió bien.",
    "answer": "attendant, aide",
    "answerDetails": "All the attendants said the meeting went off well."
  },
  {
    "id": 3209,
    "question": "penal",
    "questionDetails": "El reo tuvo que cumplir 4 años en el penal de Santa María.",
    "answer": "prison",
    "answerDetails": "The criminal had to serve four years in Santa Maria prison."
  },
  {
    "id": 3210,
    "question": "porquería",
    "questionDetails": "Para mí, esta sopa no es nada más que una porquería aderezada.",
    "answer": "muck, crud, goo",
    "answerDetails": "As far as I’m concerned, this soup is just flavoured muck."
  },
  {
    "id": 3211,
    "question": "permítame",
    "answer": "allow me"
  },
  {
    "id": 3212,
    "question": "encantó",
    "questionDetails": "Por cierto, a todos nos encantó su espectáculo.",
    "answer": "loved, absolutely loved, delighted",
    "answerDetails": "By the way, we all loved your show."
  },
  {
    "id": 3213,
    "question": "víctimas",
    "questionDetails": "Esta sala es para las víctimas de caídas aéreas.",
    "answer": "victims, casualties, vics",
    "answerDetails": "This ward is reserved for air crash victims."
  },
  {
    "id": 3214,
    "question": "hablarle",
    "questionDetails": "Todo lo que haces andar y hablarle a la gente.",
    "answer": "talk",
    "answerDetails": "All you do is walk around and talk to people."
  },
  {
    "id": 3215,
    "question": "periodistas",
    "questionDetails": "Los periodistas rodearon a la actriz haciéndole preguntas.",
    "answer": "press",
    "answerDetails": "The press surrounded the actress asking her questions."
  },
  {
    "id": 3216,
    "question": "enfrentar",
    "questionDetails": "Debemos trabajar como comunidad para enfrentar el problema del acoso Escolar.",
    "answer": "tackle, pit",
    "answerDetails": "We should work as a community to tackle the problem of bullying."
  },
  {
    "id": 3217,
    "question": "hermanas",
    "questionDetails": "Extraño a mis hermanos y hermanas.",
    "answer": "sisters",
    "answerDetails": "I miss my brothers and sisters."
  },
  {
    "id": 3218,
    "question": "envidia",
    "questionDetails": "Francia tiene una industria cinematográfica que es la envidia de Europa.",
    "answer": "envy",
    "answerDetails": "France has a film industry that is the envy of Europe."
  },
  {
    "id": 3219,
    "question": "logramos",
    "questionDetails": "Lo logramos, a pesar de todos los obstáculos.",
    "answer": "we made it",
    "answerDetails": "We made it, in spite of all the obstacles."
  },
  {
    "id": 3220,
    "question": "gustas",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que le gustas.",
    "answer": "like",
    "answerDetails": "I think you like her."
  },
  {
    "id": 3221,
    "question": "casarse",
    "questionDetails": "Fue a casarse con la hija del rey.",
    "answer": "wed",
    "answerDetails": "He was to wed the King’s daughter."
  },
  {
    "id": 3222,
    "question": "asesinos",
    "questionDetails": "La gente necesita alivio o se vuelven asesinos.",
    "answer": "murderers, killers, assassins",
    "answerDetails": "People need relief or they become murderers."
  },
  {
    "id": 3223,
    "question": "recuerde",
    "questionDetails": "Recuerde, toda esa sal y arena.",
    "answer": "remember, remind, recall",
    "answerDetails": "But remember, all that salt and grime."
  },
  {
    "id": 3224,
    "question": "avisa",
    "questionDetails": "Avisa a todos, la clave a sido robada.",
    "answer": "warns, alerts",
    "answerDetails": "Warns of all, the key to been stolen."
  },
  {
    "id": 3225,
    "question": "tumba",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando los arqueólogos entraron a la tumba, la momia salió de golpe del sarcófago.",
    "answer": "tomb, grave",
    "answerDetails": "When the archaeologists entered the tomb, the mummy burst out of the sarcophagus."
  },
  {
    "id": 3226,
    "question": "denunciar",
    "questionDetails": "Vamos a denunciar todo.",
    "answer": "denounce",
    "answerDetails": "We are going to denounce everything."
  },
  {
    "id": 3227,
    "question": "angustia",
    "questionDetails": "Una causa importante de angustia entre los habitantes de una ciudad es el alza del precio de los alquileres.",
    "answer": "distress",
    "answerDetails": "A main cause of distress for city dwellers is rising rents."
  },
  {
    "id": 3228,
    "question": "sano",
    "questionDetails": "Un desprecio sano por la autoridad.",
    "answer": "healthy, sound",
    "answerDetails": "A healthy contempt for authority."
  },
  {
    "id": 3229,
    "question": "caiga",
    "questionDetails": "Queremos que caiga en sus manos.",
    "answer": "fall, drop",
    "answerDetails": "We want it to fall into their hands."
  },
  {
    "id": 3230,
    "question": "saludos",
    "questionDetails": "El dorso de la postal decía: “Saludos desde Barcelona”.",
    "answer": "greetings, regards",
    "answerDetails": "The back of the postcard said: “Greetings from Barcelona.”."
  },
  {
    "id": 3231,
    "question": "cajas",
    "questionDetails": "Nuestro futuro está en esas cajas.",
    "answer": "boxes, crates, cases",
    "answerDetails": "Our future is in those boxes."
  },
  {
    "id": 3232,
    "question": "comisión",
    "questionDetails": "Su primera comisión como escritora independiente fue escribir una obra para una compañía de teatro.",
    "answer": "commission",
    "answerDetails": "For her first commission as a freelance writer, she wrote a play for a theater company."
  },
  {
    "id": 3233,
    "question": "claras",
    "questionDetails": "Varios detalles de la historia nunca llegan a ser claras.",
    "answer": "clear",
    "answerDetails": "Several details of the story never become clear."
  },
  {
    "id": 3234,
    "question": "haberle",
    "questionDetails": "Deberías haberle devuelto al hombre su dinero.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "You should have given that man his money back."
  },
  {
    "id": 3235,
    "question": "cómoda",
    "questionDetails": "Puse tu suéter azul en el cajón de abajo de la cómoda.",
    "answer": "dresser, commode",
    "answerDetails": "I put your blue sweater in the bottom drawer of the dresser."
  },
  {
    "id": 3236,
    "question": "muchísima",
    "questionDetails": "A vuestro favor tenéis que nos ve muchísima gente.",
    "answer": "many",
    "answerDetails": "The good thing is that many people see us."
  },
  {
    "id": 3237,
    "question": "revista",
    "questionDetails": "Solía leer revistas para adolescentes cuando tenía 15 años.",
    "answer": "magazine, journal, revue",
    "answerDetails": "I used to read magazines for teenagers when I was 15."
  },
  {
    "id": 3238,
    "question": "lleves",
    "questionDetails": "Necesito que me lleves a casa.",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "I need you to take me home."
  },
  {
    "id": 3239,
    "question": "insoportable",
    "questionDetails": "El calor se estaba volviendo insoportable.",
    "answer": "unbearable, excruciating, insupportable",
    "answerDetails": "The heat was getting unbearable."
  },
  {
    "id": 3240,
    "question": "cuchillo",
    "questionDetails": "Aquí al costado, un cuchillo.",
    "answer": "knife",
    "answerDetails": "In the side here, flat throwing knife."
  },
  {
    "id": 3241,
    "question": "mapa",
    "questionDetails": "Creció en una ciudad de Hick, justo al lado del mapa.",
    "answer": "map",
    "answerDetails": "She grew up in a hick town, right off the map."
  },
  {
    "id": 3242,
    "question": "ideal",
    "questionDetails": "Si nos puedes recoger a las 8 am, eso sería ideal.",
    "answer": "perfect",
    "answerDetails": "If you could pick us up at 8 A.M., that would be perfect."
  },
  {
    "id": 3243,
    "question": "conociste",
    "questionDetails": "La conociste de niños, ¿no?",
    "answer": "you knew",
    "answerDetails": "You knew her when you were kids, didn’t you?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3244,
    "question": "sensible",
    "questionDetails": "El nuevo método de detección de proteínas era más sensible que los anteriores.",
    "answer": "sensitive, responsive, noticeable",
    "answerDetails": "The new method of protein detection was more sensitive than earlier ones."
  },
  {
    "id": 3245,
    "question": "busqué",
    "questionDetails": "Fui tras el incendio y busqué.",
    "answer": "searched, looked",
    "answerDetails": "I went there right after the fire and searched."
  },
  {
    "id": 3246,
    "question": "guardado",
    "questionDetails": "El archivo ha sido guardado.",
    "answer": "saved, kept, guarded",
    "answerDetails": "The file is saved."
  },
  {
    "id": 3247,
    "question": "pasear",
    "questionDetails": "A la nueva mamá le encanta pasear por el barrio con su bebé.",
    "answer": "walking",
    "answerDetails": "The new mom loves walking around the neighborhood with her baby."
  },
  {
    "id": 3248,
    "question": "cumplido",
    "questionDetails": "Hacer un cumplido a alguien.",
    "answer": "compliment",
    "answerDetails": "To pay somebody a compliment."
  },
  {
    "id": 3249,
    "question": "iría",
    "answer": "Go"
  },
  {
    "id": 3250,
    "question": "seguía",
    "questionDetails": "En la escuela, seguía las instrucciones de la maestra cada día.",
    "answer": "she followed",
    "answerDetails": "In school, she followed the teacher’s directions every day."
  },
  {
    "id": 3251,
    "question": "controlado",
    "answer": "controlled"
  },
  {
    "id": 3252,
    "question": "pesa",
    "questionDetails": "¿Cuál la pesa más pesada que has levantado?",
    "answer": "dumbbell",
    "answerDetails": "What’s the heaviest dumbbell you’ve ever lifted?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3253,
    "question": "aprendiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Quizás estamos aprendiendo el arte de abarcar.",
    "answer": "learning, Iearning",
    "answerDetails": "Maybe we are learning the art of embracing."
  },
  {
    "id": 3254,
    "question": "disfruten",
    "answer": "Enjoy"
  },
  {
    "id": 3255,
    "question": "hacerles",
    "answer": "make them"
  },
  {
    "id": 3256,
    "question": "invita",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca nos invita a compartir las cosas.",
    "answer": "invites, encourages, invitation",
    "answerDetails": "She never invites us to share things."
  },
  {
    "id": 3257,
    "question": "habrán",
    "questionDetails": "Muchos ya te habrán dicho eso.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "I guess a lot of people have told you that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3258,
    "question": "técnica",
    "questionDetails": "El usa una extraña técnica.",
    "answer": "technique",
    "answerDetails": "He uses a strange technique."
  },
  {
    "id": 3259,
    "question": "huesos",
    "questionDetails": "Siempre que comemos pollo, al día siguiente hago un caldo con los huesos.",
    "answer": "carcass",
    "answerDetails": "Whenever we have chicken, I make a stock with the carcass the following Day."
  },
  {
    "id": 3260,
    "question": "pinche",
    "questionDetails": "Pinche aquí si necesita ayuda.",
    "answer": "click, scullion, puncture",
    "answerDetails": "Click here if you need assistance."
  },
  {
    "id": 3261,
    "question": "ana",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Mi madre se llama Ana!.",
    "answer": "anna",
    "answerDetails": "Anna is my mother’s name!."
  },
  {
    "id": 3262,
    "question": "autoridades",
    "questionDetails": "Hay autoridades más altas.",
    "answer": "authorities, officials",
    "answerDetails": "There are higher authorities."
  },
  {
    "id": 3263,
    "question": "fresco",
    "questionDetails": "Tomar un poco de aire fresco.",
    "answer": "fresh, cool, crisp",
    "answerDetails": "To get some fresh air."
  },
  {
    "id": 3264,
    "question": "garcía",
    "answer": "Garcia"
  },
  {
    "id": 3265,
    "question": "examen",
    "questionDetails": "A José le fue bien en el examen y será admitido a la maestría.",
    "answer": "examination",
    "answerDetails": "Jose did well on the examination and will be admitted to the Master’s program."
  },
  {
    "id": 3266,
    "question": "delincuente",
    "questionDetails": "Tu amigo era un delincuente.",
    "answer": "criminal",
    "answerDetails": "Your friend was a criminal."
  },
  {
    "id": 3267,
    "question": "veré",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando esté en Londres, veré Big Ben.",
    "answer": "i will see",
    "answerDetails": "When I am in London, I will see Big Ben."
  },
  {
    "id": 3268,
    "question": "pobrecito",
    "questionDetails": "El pobrecito no ha tenido nada para comer.",
    "answer": "poor fellow, poor",
    "answerDetails": "Poor fellow hasn’t had anything to eat."
  },
  {
    "id": 3269,
    "question": "aparezca",
    "questionDetails": "Debes hacer que aparezca en el lugar, …",
    "answer": "appears, displayed",
    "answerDetails": "You must make with that it appears in the place, …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3270,
    "question": "avisas",
    "answer": "Warn"
  },
  {
    "id": 3271,
    "question": "famosa",
    "questionDetails": "Llego a conversar con gente famosa como usted.",
    "answer": "famous",
    "answerDetails": "I get to talk to famous people like you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3272,
    "question": "acepta",
    "answer": "do you take"
  },
  {
    "id": 3273,
    "question": "manejando",
    "answer": "Driving"
  },
  {
    "id": 3274,
    "question": "temo",
    "questionDetails": "Me temo que podrías estar en lo cierto.",
    "answer": "fear, afraid, ‘m afraid",
    "answerDetails": "I fear you may be right."
  },
  {
    "id": 3275,
    "question": "despacito",
    "questionDetails": "Alguien me dijo despacito en el oído: “No te muevas”.",
    "answer": "softly",
    "answerDetails": "Someone said softly in my ear: “Don’t move.”."
  },
  {
    "id": 3276,
    "question": "caigo",
    "questionDetails": "Si yo caigo, todos caen conmigo.",
    "answer": "fall",
    "answerDetails": "I take the fall, everybody takes the fall."
  },
  {
    "id": 3277,
    "question": "plano",
    "questionDetails": "Si quieres tener el vientre plano, tienes que hacer abdominales.",
    "answer": "flat, blueprint",
    "answerDetails": "If you want a flat stomach, you have to do crunches."
  },
  {
    "id": 3278,
    "question": "prestar",
    "questionDetails": "¿Prestará la empresa el servicio de interpretación?",
    "answer": "provide, render",
    "answerDetails": "Will the company provide an interpreting service?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3279,
    "question": "temporada",
    "questionDetails": "La temporada de Cricket inglés está casi sobre nosotros.",
    "answer": "season, series",
    "answerDetails": "The English cricket season is almost upon us."
  },
  {
    "id": 3280,
    "question": "interesado",
    "questionDetails": "Estamos interesados en motivar a los alumnos a aprender idiomas.",
    "answer": "concerned, keen",
    "answerDetails": "We are concerned with encouraging students to learn foreign languages."
  },
  {
    "id": 3281,
    "question": "soportar",
    "questionDetails": "Existen metales que pueden soportar temperaturas enormemente elevadas.",
    "answer": "withstand, endure, abide",
    "answerDetails": "There are metals that can withstand tremendous heat."
  },
  {
    "id": 3282,
    "question": "hablaron",
    "questionDetails": "Los niños se metieron en problemas porque hablaron mientras lo hacía la profesora.",
    "answer": "they talked",
    "answerDetails": "The kids got in trouble because they talked while the teacher was talking."
  },
  {
    "id": 3283,
    "question": "decides",
    "questionDetails": "Tú decides a quién pertenece.",
    "answer": "decide",
    "answerDetails": "You decide who it belongs to."
  },
  {
    "id": 3284,
    "question": "soledad",
    "questionDetails": "La soledad de la granja.",
    "answer": "loneliness",
    "answerDetails": "The loneliness of the farm."
  },
  {
    "id": 3285,
    "question": "oídos",
    "questionDetails": "Pónganse esto en los oídos.",
    "answer": "ears, hearing",
    "answerDetails": "Put these in your ears."
  },
  {
    "id": 3286,
    "question": "pintura",
    "questionDetails": "Por fin terminé la pintura para mi clase de arte.",
    "answer": "painting",
    "answerDetails": "I finally finished the painting for my art class."
  },
  {
    "id": 3287,
    "question": "drama",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo querías ese drama.",
    "answer": "drama, tragedy",
    "answerDetails": "You just wanted that drama."
  },
  {
    "id": 3288,
    "question": "inventar",
    "questionDetails": "Con el tiempo, inventaron herramientas para facilitarse el trabajo.",
    "answer": "contrive",
    "answerDetails": "Eventually, they contrived some tools to make their work easier."
  },
  {
    "id": 3289,
    "question": "bajas",
    "questionDetails": "Las bajas sufridas durante la invasión de Normandía llegan a los cientos de miles.",
    "answer": "losses",
    "answerDetails": "The losses suffered during the invasion of Normandy are in the hundreds of thousands."
  },
  {
    "id": 3290,
    "question": "superar",
    "questionDetails": "Las acciones de la compañía superaron a las de la competencia.",
    "answer": "outperform",
    "answerDetails": "The company’s stock outperformed its competitors."
  },
  {
    "id": 3291,
    "question": "pierdas",
    "questionDetails": "No pierdas la esperanza.",
    "answer": "lose, miss, waste",
    "answerDetails": "Do not lose heart."
  },
  {
    "id": 3292,
    "question": "ganaste",
    "questionDetails": "Pero tú ganaste,y se hizo justicia.",
    "answer": "won, earned",
    "answerDetails": "But hey, you won, justice was done."
  },
  {
    "id": 3293,
    "question": "preferiría",
    "questionDetails": "Preferiría comer un gusano antes que darle un beso.",
    "answer": "i would rather",
    "answerDetails": "I would rather eat a worm than kiss him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3294,
    "question": "grabando",
    "questionDetails": "Sigue grabando y envíalo a la estación.",
    "answer": "recording, taping, videotaping",
    "answerDetails": "Just keep recording and sending it to the station."
  },
  {
    "id": 3295,
    "question": "explicarte",
    "questionDetails": "Puedo explicarte la escultura.",
    "answer": "explain",
    "answerDetails": "I can explain the statue."
  },
  {
    "id": 3296,
    "question": "queridos",
    "questionDetails": "Así como nuestros queridos hijos.",
    "answer": "dear, ones, darlings",
    "answerDetails": "As do our dear children."
  },
  {
    "id": 3297,
    "question": "independiente",
    "questionDetails": "La legislatura y la judicatura son independientes entre sí.",
    "answer": "independent, separate, freelance",
    "answerDetails": "The legislature and the judicature are independent of one another."
  },
  {
    "id": 3298,
    "question": "entendemos",
    "questionDetails": "Así que todos entendemos lo solo que se siente.",
    "answer": "understand",
    "answerDetails": "So we can all understand how lonely you must be."
  },
  {
    "id": 3299,
    "question": "enseño",
    "questionDetails": "Yo enseño esos cursos.",
    "answer": "teach, spanked",
    "answerDetails": "I teach those courses."
  },
  {
    "id": 3300,
    "question": "murieron",
    "answer": "Died"
  }
]